让我们来研究图像强度如何沿着我在这里用红色显示的线条变化
Let’s investigate how image intensity varies along the line that I have shown here in red
特别是，让我们关注P尾部发生的事情。如果我们看一下
and, in particular, let’s focus on what happens here at the tail of the P. If we look
在这里的强度分布和这些像素值，这些灰度值是双倍的
at the intensity profile here and these pixel values, these grey scale values are double
黑色和白色之间的精度值在零之间变化，我们看到它
precision values that vary between zero for black and one for white, and we see that it
以0.2左右的低值开始。而在黑漆-背景
starts off with a low value of around 0.2. Whereas on the black paint — the background
标志-当我们穿过白色涂料时，它们上升到大约0.8的值
of the sign — they rise up to a value of around 0.8 and when we cross the white paint, which
是P的尾部，然后再次下降到低背景值
is the tail of the P, and then fall off again to low background values
回到黑漆上。我们可能有兴趣看水平梯度和
back onto the black paint. We might be interested in looking at the horizontal gradient and
我们可以将梯度近似为左侧像素与其邻居之间的差异
we can approximate the gradient as the difference between a pixel and its neighbour on the left-hand
side-梯度的简单数值近似。但是，这不是非常对称的
side — a simple numerical approximation to the gradient. However, this is not a very symmetrical
想一想的方法。所以我们可以用这种方式表示它：强度
way to think about this. So instead we can represent it this way: the intensity in the
像素U的水平方向是其右侧的邻居之间的差
horizontal direction of pixel U is the difference between its neighbour on the right-hand side
和它在左侧的邻居除以2.这将代表水平梯度。
and its neighbour on the left-hand side, divided by 2. This would represent the horizontal gradient.
现在我们以这种形式表达了渐变
Now the gradient expressed in this form we
可以写为内核-它是一个由1乘3矩阵表示的小内核。如果我们申请
can write as a kernel — it is a small kernel represented by a 1 by 3 matrix. If we apply
这个内核到输入图像的结果将是一个像素包含的输出图像
this kernel to the input image the result would be an output image whose pixels comprise
相应点的水平梯度。
the horizontal gradient at the corresponding point.
这是一个类似于我们以前见过的动画;在红色，我们看到输入窗口
Here is an animation similar to ones we have seen before; in red, we see the input window
从左到右，从上到下穿过图像。因为它正在移动我们
marching across the image from left to right and from top to bottom. As it is moving we
计算输出值并将它们放入输出图像。再次注意
are computing the output values and dropping them into the output image. Note again that
我们不计算左手边缘和右手边缘
we are not computing the left-hand edge and right-hand edge of the
输出图像，因为这是输入窗口从输入图像中掉落的地方。我们可以看到
output image because this is where the input window falls off the input image. We can see
在计算梯度时，我们可以看到温和的水平梯度区域
the gradient being computed, we can see areas of gentle horizontal gradient, we can see
水平梯度更强的区域，我们有这种连续性，我们可以看到
the areas of much stronger horizontal gradient where we have this continuity and we can see
梯度为负的区域。让我们将它应用于我们的形象
areas where the gradient is negative. Let’s apply this to the image that we were
看一下之前，我们可以很简单地使用工具箱功能iconv。
looking at earlier and we can do that quite simply using the tool box function iconv.
我们传入第一个参数，即内核，第二个参数，即
We pass in the first argument, which is the kernel, and the second argument, which is
图片。我们在这里看到的是左手
the image. What we can see here is that the left-hand
字母的边缘编码为蓝色;这意味着它们具有正梯度
edges of the letters are coded blue; that means they have positive gradient that is
强度从背景的黑暗变为字母的白色。
where the intensity is changing from the dark of the background to the white of the letters.
在字母的右侧，强度从白色下降到
On the right-hand side of the letters where the intensity falls from white down to the
深色背景它有一个负值，这显示为红色。那么内核是什么
dark background it has got a negative value and this is shown as red. So what this kernel
正在做的是突出显示场景中的垂直线，因为有垂直线
is doing is highlighting vertical lines within the scene because vertical lines have got
强烈的水平梯度。我用下标u（Iu）表示这个图像。
a strong horizontal gradient. I denote this image as I subscript u (Iu).
这是表示图像渐变的常用方法。下标代表方向
This is a common way to denote image gradients. The subscript represents the direction in
正在计算梯度。现在我们可以通过旋转做一个非常相似的事情
which the gradient is being computed. Now we can do a very similar thing by rotating
内核，现在我们可以计算垂直方向的渐变。所以内核现在
the kernel and now we can compute the gradient in the vertical direction. So the kernel now
是我们用来计算水平梯度的内核的转置。它会允许
is the transpose of the kernel we used to compute horizontal gradient. It will allow
我们计算垂直梯度。
us to compute vertical gradient.
现在，我们可以将它应用到我们的企鹅标志，这就是内核的样子和这个
Now, we can apply that to our penguin sign, this is what the kernel looks like and this
是输出的样子。它与我们之前看到的有些相似之处。和我们一样
is what the output looks like. It has some similarities to what we saw before. As we
在列中向下移动，我们看到字母的顶部是蓝色的，这表明
move down in a column, we see that the tops of letters are blue and this indicates that
他们有一个强烈的正梯度。请记住，在图像中垂直坐标
they have got a strong positive gradient. Remember that in images the vertical coordinate
向下增加。所以在一封信的顶部，我们正从黑暗的背景移动到
increases downwards. So at the top of a letter we are moving from the dark background onto
白漆，所以我们有一个强烈的正梯度。在那里的字母的底部
the white paint and so we have a strong positive gradient. On the bottom of the letters there
如果你从白色油漆上掉落到黑色背景上，则是一个强烈的负梯度。
is a strong negative gradient if you fall off the white paint down onto the black background.
因此垂直渐变图像突出显示了图像中的水平线。我们
So the vertical gradient image has highlighted the horizontal lines within the image. We
可以使用几乎与之前相同的函数在MATLAB中进行计算，除非我们进行了转置
can compute this in MATLAB using almost the same function as before except we have transposed
内核。内核是一个1乘3的矩阵，我们使用MATLAB的转置运算符
the kernel. The kernel is a 1 by 3 matrix and we use MATLAB’s transpose operator the
引号用于将该内核转换为3×1矩阵。
quote symbol in order to transpose that kernel into a 3 by 1 matrix.
在图像处理中使用的一个非常常见的内核称为Sobel内核，它有一些
A very common kernel used in image processing is called the Sobel kernel, and it has some
与我们之前使用的简单内核相似。我想要考虑这个内核
similarities to the simple kernel that we used before. I like to think of this kernel
计算当前行上的水平梯度并将其与水平线平均
as computing the horizontal gradient on the current line and averaging that with the horizontal
在上面和下面的线上的渐变。我们可以获得这个内核的价值
gradient on the line above and on the line below. We can obtain the value of this kernel
使用工具箱功能ksobel。如果我将此功能应用于我的企鹅图像，我可以获得
using the tool box function ksobel. If I apply this function to our penguin image I can obtain
这里显示的水平渐变图像看起来非常类似于水平
a horizontal gradient image that is shown here, which looks quite similar to the horizontal
渐渐我们只是看着。函数isobel，我们传递一个图像，它返回一个
gradient we just looked at. The function isobel, we pass it an image and it returns both a
水平梯度图像和垂直梯度图像。
horizontal gradient image and a vertical gradient image.
图像中非常重要的特征-人造图像中非常常见的特征
A really important feature in an image — a very common feature in images of man-made
场景-我们称之为边缘。我要做的是加载我们拥有的图像
scenes — are what we call edges. What I am going to do is to load an image that we have
之前看过并展示过，这里有关于企鹅的标志，还有什么
seen before and to display that, and here is the sign about penguins again, and what
我要做的是沿着大致水平线观察强度分布
I am going to do is to look at an intensity profile along roughly a horizontal line from
在这里，我们看到的是强度从一开始就具有较低的价值
here to there, and what we see is the intensity has got a low value to start with and then
当我们穿过标志上的每一块白色油漆时，我们看到强度上升。
as we cross each of the pieces of white paint on the sign we see the intensity goes up.
现在让我们放大一点，它有点太忙了。我要扩大
Now let’s zoom in a little bit on that, it is a little bit too busy. I am going to expand
这个地区，这是“看”这个词的开头，也是我们看到的
this region here, which is the beginning of the word ‘look’, and what we see quite
这里显然是像素具有相当低的值，小于0.2，这是背景。
clearly here is that the pixels have got quite a low value, less than 0.2 which is the background.
标志的深色背景移动到0.6左右，0.7左右。我们穿过的白色油漆
The dark background of the sign moves up to around 0.6, 0.7. The white paint as we cross
字母L-down再次变为0.2，然后像素值随着我们交叉而增加
the letter L—down again to a value of 0.2, and then pixel value increases as we cross
剩下的信件。我们可以看到，当我们从黑暗走向光明时
the remaining letters. What we can see is that as we move from the dark to the light
强度增长很快。然后它在另一边迅速下降
the intensity increases quite rapidly. Then it falls quite rapidly on the other side of
这个角色，所以我们将探索这种渐变或变化率的想法
the character, so we are going to explore this idea of gradient or the rate of change
当我们在标志上水平移动时，在灰度级。
at the grey level as we move horizontally across the sign.
通常在图像处理中，我们感兴趣的是有很多图像的区域
Often in image processing we are interested in areas of the image where there is a lot
渐变。我们不关心它是水平的还是垂直的;我们不在乎
of gradient. We don’t care whether it is horizontal or vertical; we don’t care whether
这是积极的还是消极的。我们只想知道哪里有很多渐变。
it is positive or negative. We just want to know where there is a lot of gradient.
这可以通过计算平方和的平方根来计算得非常简单
And this is computed quite simply by computing the square root of the sum of the squares
水平和垂直渐变的结果，并产生这样的图像。
of the horizontal and vertical gradients and results in an image like this.
大多数是黑色的，因为背景上没有太多的渐变。那里
Most of it is black because there isn’t much gradient over the background. Where there
在字母边缘有很多渐变，这个函数有很高的价值。所以
is a lot of gradient around the edges of letters this function has got a very high value. So
这是一个很好的操作符，用于突出显示场景中对象的边缘。和我们
this is a great operator for highlighting the edges of objects within a scene. And we
可以使用函数isobel获得这样的图像，没有输出参数。
can obtain an image like this using the function isobel with no output arguments.
我们可能也对最大梯度的方向感兴趣;在这个图像像素
We might also be interested in the direction of maximum gradient; in this image pixels
在水平方向上每个像素增加10个值，每个像素增加5个
are increasing by a value of 10 every pixel in the horizontal direction and by 5 every
像素垂直。因此，最大梯度变化的方向是在这个方向上，26°
pixel vertically. So the direction of maximum gradient change is in this direction, 26°
关于水平。现在我们可以应用相同的技术
with respect to horizontal. Now we can apply that same technique to the
我们之前计算过的索贝尔图像。我们可以计算一个渐变图像，即弧形
Sobel image that we computed before. We can compute a gradient image and that is the arc
垂直梯度图像元素的切线明智地除以水平梯度图像。
tangent of the vertical gradient image element wise divided by the horizontal gradient image.
它看起来有点太忙了，所以让我们放大字母P.
It looks a little bit too busy, so let’s zoom in on the letter P.
如果我们观察P的左边缘的梯度方向，我们就会看到它
And if we look at the gradient direction on the left-hand edge of the P, we see that it
梯度方向值为0.它被编码为白色。
has got a gradient direction value of 0. It’s coded as white.
因此，如果我们查看此处的颜色条，我们可以看到0对应于零梯度
So if we look at the colour bar over here, we can see that 0 corresponds to zero gradient
角度，我们期望这封信的这一面;渐变在增加
angle and we expect this on this side of the letter; the gradient is increasing in the
水平方向从左到右。在字母的另一边渐变
horizontal direction from left to right. On the other side of the letter the gradient
实际上是从右到左增加，因为正是在这一点上我们正在追随
is, in fact, increasing from right to left because it is at this point that we are following
从高白值到暗值。所以渐变是从右到左
from the high white value down to the dark value. So the gradient is right to left and
我们可以在字母的这一边看到渐变角度加上π，哪个
we can see on this side of the letter the gradient angles are either plus π, which
显示为深蓝色或负π，显示为深红色。
are shown as dark blue or negative π, which is shown as dark red.